Oliver Wolcott, Jr. Papers
Connecticut Historical Society
- III. United States Government appointments
  - Wolcott's document dividers., [between 1795 - 1800]; (2 items) (Box 47, Folder 10)
  - U. S. Treasury Department. The Bank of the United States. Quarterly bank statements in record book., 1792 - 1800; (1 item) (Box 47, Folder 11)
  - U. S. Treasury Department. Bank of the United States. List of Certificates issued by the Register of the Treasury in lieu of sundry receipts given by the Cashiers of the Banks of Massachusetts, New York and Maryland, for monies therein deposited towards subscriptions to the Bank of the United States., 1791; (1 item) (Box 47, Folder 12)
  - Circuit Court papers., April - July, 1801; (14 items) (Box 47, Folder 13)
  - Circuit Court papers., August - December, 1801; (18 items) (Box 47, Folder 14)
  - Circuit Court papers., 1802; (3 items) (Box 47, Folder 15)
- IV. Business papers
  - Invoices for articles shipped on the American ship, Allegany., 1803; (4 items) (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - The Allegany, January - May, 1804; (30 items) (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - The Allegany., June - December, 1804; (36 items) (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - The Allegany., 1805; (14 items) (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - The Triton., 1803; (4 items) (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - The Triton., January - April, 1804; (13 items) (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - The Triton., May, 1804; (17 items) (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - The Triton., June - December, 1804; (19 items) (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - The Triton., 1805 - 1806; (11 items) (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - The Virginia., 1805; (16 items) (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - The Virginia., 1806 - 1807; (5 items) (Box 48, Folder 11)
  - The China Trade. Accounts of exports, imports; lists of vessels., 1803 - 1811; (17 items) (Box 48, Folder 12)
  - The China Trade., 1805 - 1811; (19 items) (Box 47, Folder 13)
  - The China Trade. Statements of Storage on Sales; current accounts., 1808 - 1814; (5 items) (Box 48, Folder 14)
  - Wolcott's document dividers. "Allegany's Cargo," "Brig American Consul's papers," "Ship Triton's papers, Thomas Carberry, Master," and "Ship Virginia, Spear Master from Calcutta.", 1803 - 1814; (4 items) (Box 48, Folder 15)
  - The Trident., [1805?]; (17 items) (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - The Trident., 1805; (26 items) (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - The Trident., January - March, 1806; (29 items) (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - The Trident., April, 1806; (38 items) (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - The Trident., May - December, 1806; (17 items) (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - The Trident. Account of the Ship Trident's Expenses While at Canton., July - December, 1806; (1 items) (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - The Trident., 1807; (23 items) (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - The Trident., 1807; (46 items) (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - The Trident., 1807; (25 items) (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - The Trident., 1808; (33 items) (Box 49, Folder 10)
  - The Trident., January - April, 1809; (51 items) (Box 49, Folder 11)
  - The Trident., May, 1809; (26 items) (Box 49, Folder 12)
  - The Trident., June, 1809 - January, 1811; (15 items) (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - The Trident., 1809 - 1812; (36 items) (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Accounts and invoices., 1802 - 1803; (9 items) (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Accounts and invoices., 1804 - 1807; (25 items) (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Accounts and invoices., 1808 - 1809; (31 items) (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Accounts and invoices., 1809 - 1810; (34 items) (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - Insurance policies., 1805; (4 items) (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Insurance policies., 1806; (10 items) (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - Insurance policies., 1807; (2 items) (Box 50, Folder 9)
  - Insurance policies., 1808; (8 items) (Box 50, Folder 10)
  - Insurance policies., 1809; (14 items) (Box 50, Folder 11)
  - Insurance policies., 1810; (8 items) (Box 50, Folder 12)
  - Insurance policies., 1810; (5 items) (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Insurance policies., 1811; (4 items) (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Bank of the United States., 1805; 1810 - 1811; (8 items) (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Bank of the United States., February, 1812; (13 items) (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Bank of America., March, 1812 - May, 1814; (6 items) (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Bank of America., January - February, 1820; (16 items) (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Bank of America., March, 1820; (10 items) (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - Bank of America., 1824; (9 items) (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - Phoenix Branch Bank., 1815 - 1821; (14 items) (Box 51, Folder 9)
  - Phoenix Branch Bank., 1822 - 1823; (8 items) (Box 51, Folder 10)
  - Phoenix Branch Bank., 1824; (7 items) (Box 51, Folder 11)
  - Phoenix Branch Bank., 1826; (14 items) (Box 51, Folder 12)
  - Phoenix Branch Bank., 1827; (16 items) (Box 51, Folder 13)
  - Phoenix Branch Bank., 1828 - 1831; (8 items) (Box 51, Folder 14)
  - Frederick and Oliver Wolcott, Jr. financial papers., 1805 - 1811; (3 items) (Box 51, Folder 15)
  - Frederick and Oliver Wolcott, Jr. financial papers., 1817 - 1819; (4 items) (Box 51, Folder 16)
  - Frederick and Oliver Wolcott, Jr. financial papers., 1821; (19 items) (Box 51, Folder 17)
  - Litchfield Woolen Manufactory., 1823; (3 items) (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - Litchfield Woolen Manufactory., 1824 - 1829; (10 items) (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - Estate of James Watson., 1787 - 1805; (11 items) (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - Estate of James Watson. Memorandum and account of the Workmanship and Materials of erecting a house for James Watson Esquire fronting the Battery in State Street which was begun May, 21, 1805., (1 item) (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - Estate of James Watson., January - May, 1806; (14 items) (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - Estate of James Watson., June - December, 1806; (23 items) (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - Estate of James Watson., 1807 - 1824; (20 items) (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - Estate of James Watson. Wolcott's document divider., 1806 - 1824; (1 item) (Box 52, Folder 8)
- V. Personal Papers
  - Personal papers, legal documents., 1785 - 1787; (3 items) (Box 52, Folder 9)
  - Personal papers including legal documents and receipts., 1780 - 1806; (18 items) (Box 52, Folder 10)
  - Personal papers including receipts, promissory notes, and deduction of titles., 1799 - 1808; (24 items) (Box 52, Folder 11)
  - Personal papers., 1807 - 1810; (31 items) (Box 52, Folder 12)
  - Personal papers including receipts and promissory notes., 1811 - 1814; (23 items) (Box 52, Folder 13)
  - Personal papers., 1769 - 1815; (21 items) (Box 52, Folder 14)
  - Personal papers., 1816 - 1817; (8 items) (Box 52, Folder 15)
  - Personal papers., 1817 - 1827; (12 items) (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - Personal papers, 1827 - 1831; (16 items) (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - Personal papers, deed and writ of attachment of the estate of Oliver Wolcott, Jr., 1806 - 1827; (2 items) (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - Personal papers, finances., January, 1811; (29 items) (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - Personal papers, finances., February, 1811; (6 items) (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - Personal papers, finances., March, 1811; (15 items) (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - Personal papers, finances., April, 1811; (13 items) (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - Personal papers, finances., May - June, 1811; (13 items) (Box 52, Folder 8)
  - Personal papers, finances., July - August, 1811; (18 items) (Box 52, Folder 9)
  - Personal papers, finances., September - October, 1811; (23 items) (Box 52, Folder 10)
  - Personal papers, finances., November - December, 1811; (25 items) (Box 52, Folder 11)
  - Personal papers, finances., 1812; (8 items) (Box 52, Folder 12)
  - Personal papers, finances., 1813; (18 items) (Box 52, Folder 13)
  - Personal papers, finances., 1814; (26 items) (Box 52, Folder 14)
  - Personal papers, finances., 1815; (5 items) (Box 52, Folder 15)
  - Personal papers. Awards and appointments. Oliver Wolcott, Jr.'s Yale diploma., 1781; (1 item) (Box 52, Folder 17)
  - Personal papers. Awards and appointments., 1784 - 1788; (5 items) (Box 52, Folder 18)
  - Personal papers. Awards and appointments. U. S. government appointments., 1789 - 1801; (4 items) (Box 52, Folder 18)
  - Personal papers. Awards and appointments. Honorary degrees., 1799 - 1819; (3 items) (Box 52, Folder 19)
  - Personal papers. Awards and appointments. Association memberships., 1814 - 18-?; (2 items) (Box 52, Folder 20)
  - Personal papers. Untitled sketch., 17-?; (1 items) (Box 52, Folder 21)
  - Personal papers. Commmonplace book (containing Oliver Wolcott, Jr.'s "Memorandum of the Contents of the Port Folios of Manuscripts, to be arranged anew")., 1794 - 18-?; (1 item) (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - Personal papers. Tables for writing in cypher., [17-?]; (3 items) (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - Personal papers. List of Papers of Oliver Wolcott, Jr. Books not numbered but put up., [18-?]; (2 items) (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - Personal papers. Lock of hair of George Gibbs V., September, 1816; (1 item) (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - Personal papers. Invoices and receipts, deed of warranty., 1765 - 1807; (4 items) (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - Personal papers. Printed material., 1822 - 1823; (3 items) (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - Personal papers. Plan for establishing Military Schools; Settlement between the U. S. and the several States for Expenses of the Revolutionary War., 1790 - 1815; (2 items) (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - Personal papers. Oliver Wolcott, Jr.'s jottings, draft of letter, property plan of Robert Hunter., 17-? - 1825; (5 items) (Box 54, Folder 8)
  - Personal papers. Drafts of speeches., 1825 - 1829; (3 items) (Box 54, Folder 9)
- VI. Connecticut Offices
  - Willing Morris and Company Accounts of Transactions with the Secret Committee., 1776 - 1790; (1 item) (Box 54, Folder 10)
  - Connecticut offices., 1775 - 1781; (10 items) (Box 57, Folder 11)
  - Connecticut offices., 1782 - 1783; (19 items) (Box 54, Folder 12)
  - Connecticut offices., 1787; (18 items) (Box 54, Folder 13)
  - Connecticut offices., January - October, 1788; (13 items) (Box 54, Folder 14)
  - Connecticut offices., November - December, 1788; (11 items) (Box 54, Folder 15)
  - Connecticut offices., January - June, 1789; (13 items) (Box 54, Folder 16)
  - Connecticut offices., July - December, 1789; (15 items) (Box 54, Folder 17)
  - Connecticut offices. Auditor's office., 1790 - 1791; (8 items) (Box 54, Folder 18)
  - Connecticut offices. Assistant Deputy Quartermaster General for Litchfield., July, 1780; (17 items) (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - Connecticut offices. Assistant Deputy Quartermaster General for Litchfield., August - November, 1780; (33 items) (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - Connecticut offices Assistant Deputy Quartermaster General for Litchfield., November, 1780; (41 items) (Box 55, Folder 3)
  - Connecticut offices. Assistant Deputy Quartermaster General for Litchfield., November - December, 1780; (13 items) (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - Connecticut offices. Army Forage Account., 1782; (1 item) (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - Connecticut offices. Connecticut Accounts of Duties on Writs., 1784 - 1788; (1 item) (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - Connecticut offices. Foreign creditors., 1789 - 1790; (1 items) (Box 55, Folder 7)
  - Connecticut offices. Executive., 1818 - July, 1820; (21 items) (Box 55, Folder 8)
  - Connecticut offices. Executive., August - December, 1820; (12 items) (Box 55, Folder 9)
  - Connecticut offices. Executive., January - May, 1821; (30 items) (Box 55, Folder 10)
  - Connecticut offices. Executive., June - December, 1821; (28 items) (Box 55, Folder 11)
  - Connecticut offices. Executive., January - February, 1822; (13 items) (Box 55, Folder 12)
  - Connecticut offices. Executive., March - June, 1822; (18 items) (Box 55, Folder 13)
  - Connecticut offices. Executive., July - December, 1822; (21 items) (Box 55, Folder 14)
  - Connecticut offices. Executive., January - May, 1823; (24 items) (Box 55, Folder 15)
  - Connecticut offices. Executive., June - July, 1823; (16 items) (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - Connecticut offices. Executive., August - November, 1823; (35 items) (Box 56, Folder 2)
  - Connecticut offices. Executive., January - March, 1824; (22 items) (Box 56, Folder 3)
  - Connecticut offices. Executive., April - May, 1824; (21 items) (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - Connecticut offices. Executive., June - September, 1824; (19 items) (Box 56, Folder 5)
  - Connecticut offices. Executive., October - December, 1824; (12 items) (Box 56, Folder 6)
  - Connecticut offices. Executive., January - April, 1825; (27 items) (Box 56, Folder 7)
  - Connecticut offices. Executive., May - June, 1825; (22 items) (Box 56, Folder 8)
  - Connecticut offices. Executive., August - September, 1825; (19 items) (Box 56, Folder 9)
  - Connecticut offices. Executive., October - December, 1825; (12 items) (Box 56, Folder 10)
  - Connecticut offices. Executive., 1826; (3 items) (Box 56, Folder 11)
  - Connecticut offices. Executive., 1827; (26 items) (Box 56, Folder 12)
  - Connecticut offices. Executive (Legal)., [1801?]; (30 items) (Box 56, Folder 13)
  - Connecticut offices. Executive (Legal)., 1802 - 1805; (8 items) (Box 56, Folder 14)
  - Connecticut offices. Executive (Legal)., 1805 - 1808; (9 items) (Box 56, Folder 15)
  - Connecticut offices. Executive (Legal)., 1813 - 1816; (22 items) (Box 56, Folder 16)
  - Connecticut offices. Executive (Legal)., 1817; (3 items) (Box 56, Folder 17)
  - Connecticut offices. Executive (Legal)., 1818 - 1819; (23 items) (Box 56, Folder 18)
  - Connecticut offices. Executive (Legal)., 1810 - 1812; (1 item) (Box 56, Folder 19)
  - Connecticut offices. Executive (Legal). Opinions of Judges., 1811 - 1813; (24 items) (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - Connecticut offices. Executive (Legal). Opinions of Judges., 1818 - 1819; (17 items) (Box 57, Folder 2)
- VII. Wolcott Family Papers
  - CHS correspondence with Wolcott family members., 1848 - 1880; (19 items) (Box 57, Folder 3)
  - Henry Wolcott. Wolcott Ledgers and Genealogy., 1500's - 1800's; (1 item) (Box 57, Folder 4)
  - Henry Wolcott. Notebook, part shorthand, part longhand. Transcript of shorthand by Douglas H. Shepard., 1643 - 1709; (2 items) (Box 57, Folder 5)
  - Letter book of John Stoughton (father-in-law of Oliver Wolcott, Jr.), 1762 - 1765; (1 item) (Box 57, Folder 6)
  - Oliver Wolcott, Jr. Account of expenses incurred in removal of the government from Philadelphia to Washington., 1800 - 1801; (1 item) (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - The Judgment of Paris, a Poem, by Oliver Wolcott, Jr., 1778; (1 item) (Box 58, Folder 2)
  - Notes on Wolcott Papers, George Gibbs., 1755? - 1814; (1 item) (Box 58, Folder 3)
  - Guide to Oliver Wolcott, Jr. Papers, George Gibbs., 1755? - 1814; (1 item) (Box 58, Folder 4)
  - Wolcott Family Papers. Letters to and from Wolcott family members., 1745 - 1775; (6 items) (Box 58, Folder 5)
  - Wolcott family papers. Deeds, indentures, licenses of agreement, and estate papers., 1616 - 1667; (12 items) (Box 58, Folder 6)
  - Wolcott family papers., 1670 - 1767; (15 items) (Box 58, Folder 7)
  - Wolcott family papers., 1680 - 1699; (13 items) (Box 58, Folder 8)
  - Wolcott family papers., 1700 - 1749; (15 items) (Box 58, Folder 9)
  - Wolcott family papers., 1750 - 1759; (12 items) (Box 58, Folder 10)
  - Wolcott family papers., 1760 - 1799; (10 items) (Box 58, Folder 11)
  - Wolcott family papers., 1780 - 1799; (13 items) (Box 58, Folder 12)
  - Wolcott family papers., 1842 - 1850?; (8 items) (Box 58, Folder 13)
  - Wolcott family papers. Wolcott deeds. Authority by Bacon to Robert Mynne to alienate land to Christopher Wolcott., 1616; (1 item) (Box 58, Folder 14)
  - Wolcott family papers. Wolcott deeds. Robert Mynne to Christopher Wolcott., 1619; (1 item) (Box 59, Folder 1)
  - Wolcott family papers. Wolcott deeds. Christopher Wolcott., 1623; (1 item) (Box 59, Folder 2)
  - Wolcott family papers. Wolcott deeds. Henry Wolcott deed of parcel... to Henry Wolcott, 2nd at his marriage., 1642; (1 item) (Box 59, Folder 3)
  - Wolcott family papers. Wolcott deeds. Henry Wolcott to John Wolcott., 1640; (1 item) (Box 59, Folder 4)
  - Wolcott family papers. Wolcott deeds. Lease, Henry Wolcott to John Wolcott., 1640; (1 item) (Box 59, Folder 5)
  - Wolcott family papers. Wolcott deeds. Lease Henry Wolcott to John Wolcott., 1640; (1 item) (Box 59, Folder 6)
  - Wolcott family papers. Wolcott deeds. George Best to James Hawker., 1614; (1 item) (Box 59, Folder 7)
  - Wolcott family papers. Wolcott deeds. Lease, James Hawker to Geoffrey Colburn; Deed, George Best to James Hawker., 1619; (2 items) (Box 59, Folder 8)
  - Wolcott family papers. Wolcott deeds. James Hawker to Walter Catford., 1627; (1 item) (Box 59, Folder 9)
  - Wolcott family papers. Wolcott deeds. Deed, James Russell to Henry Wolcott, 2nd., 1668; (1 items) (Box 59, Folder 10)
  - Wolcott family papers. Wolcott deeds. Thomas Clarke to Charles Jardine., 1743; (1 item) (Box 59, Folder 11)
  - Wolcott family papers. Wolcott deeds. Patent to John Stoughton., 1764; (1 item) (Box 59, Folder 12)
  - Wolcott family papers. Wolcott deeds. Oliver Wolcott to Alexander Ellis., 1795; (1 item) (Box 59, Folder 13)